<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Settle Aid Blog</title>
        <link>https://topmello.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Settle Aid Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
            <link>https://topmello.github.io/blog/welcome</link>
            <guid>https://topmello.github.io/blog/welcome</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Settle-Aid]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="settle-aid">Settle-Aid<a href="#settle-aid" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Settle-Aid" title="Direct link to Settle-Aid">​</a></h2><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="problem-statement">Problem Statement<a href="#problem-statement" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Problem Statement" title="Direct link to Problem Statement">​</a></h2><p>“Flying Grannies” in Australia are subjected to social isolation due to difficulty adapting to new surroundings. They make temporary visits to Melbourne for the purpose of looking after their grandchildren. With 30% of Australia's population originating from overseas, a minimum of 4,500 grandparents are undertaking regular brief trips to aid their families. These grandparents face challenges adapting to new environments due to language barrier and cultural shock, resulting in a tendency to remain at home. Frequently, they experience loneliness and are socially isolated, especially when their grandchildren are in school or during the early stages of their stay in Australia.</p><p>The impact of social isolation is detrimental to the well-being of grandparents, causing stress among family members and diminishing the multicultural fabric of Australian society. Given Melbourne's being a metropolitan city of diverse cultures with a significant number of grandparents, there is a dire need to facilitate connections between “Flying Grannies” and the broader community. How can we mitigate the social isolation experienced by "Flying Grannies" in Melbourne and assist them in adapting to their new surroundings?</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="persona">Persona<a href="#persona" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Persona" title="Direct link to Persona">​</a></h2><table><thead><tr><th>Attribute</th><th>Details</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Name</td><td>Dalin Yu</td></tr><tr><td>Major Responsibility</td><td>Grandma with contributory visa</td></tr><tr><td>Demographics</td><td>62 years old, Married with children and grandchildren, Non-proficient in English, Recently moved from China to Australia</td></tr><tr><td>Motivations</td><td>"Dalin wants to provide dedicated care for her grandson, ensuring her daughter able to work with peace of mind."</td></tr><tr><td>Motivations</td><td>She would embark on monthly travels with her friends if she feels less overwhelmed.</td></tr><tr><td>Pain points</td><td>Dalin is not familiar with any local activities and finds it difficult to navigate around the Melbourne city.</td></tr><tr><td>Pain points</td><td>Social isolation due to language hurdles and the challenges of adapting to a new local culture</td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>products</category>
            <category>hello</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>