<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Settle Aid Blog</title>
        <link>https://topmello.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Settle Aid Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Product Video]]></title>
            <link>https://topmello.github.io/blog/products-video</link>
            <guid>https://topmello.github.io/blog/products-video</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<video width="100%" controls=""><source src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/topmello/settle-aid-assets/main/product-vid.mp4" type="video/mp4">Your browser does not support the video tag.</video>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>products</category>
            <category>artifacts</category>
            <category>video</category>
            <category>youtube</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Artefacts]]></title>
            <link>https://topmello.github.io/blog/artefacts</link>
            <guid>https://topmello.github.io/blog/artefacts</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Background]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="background">Background<a href="#background" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Background" title="Direct link to Background">​</a></h2><p>Settle Aid is important for both "Flying Grannies" and Australian society as it improves the well-being of these grandparents, strengthens family dynamics, and enriches the multicultural fabric of Australian society.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="system-components">System Components<a href="#system-components" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to System Components" title="Direct link to System Components">​</a></h2><ul><li>Analysis and Design Report: <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/u/1/folders/1arcBiH8aXb4UXkZcHMHF3gsvGApjIN_4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Link</a></li><li>Design Artefacts: <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/u/1/folders/12U2ci-LVh7MFYuxTqAGCc7TwB0MN2w8y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Link</a></li><li>Build: <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/u/1/folders/1MESszIor3mW6dLv3uAQ8axbA9c4cLYTp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Link</a> </li><li>System Architecture and Security: <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/u/1/folders/1FlGdO2h_CC9pXnL91hzOsJKSX1t3RvIW" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Link</a> </li><li>Data Governance: <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/u/1/folders/172ae08Ama2weGeQcIglKKxn01kROsSxd" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Link</a></li><li>Risk Management: <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/u/1/folders/1dYvk0Siv2EiO_g1ghvmKZRfVIegxEVUi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Link</a></li><li>Testing: <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/u/1/folders/11drqq90oPUwboIntG-dbnjOtUJ4KpcxB" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Link</a></li><li>Team Information: <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/u/1/folders/1w3Mm5AofPde4ViVbcEUMYReExJuHiw0o" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Link</a></li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>products</category>
            <category>artifacts</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ethics]]></title>
            <link>https://topmello.github.io/blog/ethics</link>
            <guid>https://topmello.github.io/blog/ethics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Ethics Canvas]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ethics-canvas">Ethics Canvas<a href="#ethics-canvas" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Ethics Canvas" title="Direct link to Ethics Canvas">​</a></h2><p>Link to Ethics Canvas Document: <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/u/1/folders/1NgtfeWH2DmG0anxPpRwZILXTMLXW23k2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Link</a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="compliances-with-acs-code-of-conduct">Compliances with ACS Code of Conduct<a href="#compliances-with-acs-code-of-conduct" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Compliances with ACS Code of Conduct" title="Direct link to Compliances with ACS Code of Conduct">​</a></h2><p>Settle Aid strictly adheres to the ACS Code of Conduct by prioritizing privacy, security, and inclusivity in all aspects of the application. It ensures data protection, respectful cultural integration, and ethical use of technology. These include:</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="primacy-of-the-public-interest">Primacy of the Public Interest<a href="#primacy-of-the-public-interest" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Primacy of the Public Interest" title="Direct link to Primacy of the Public Interest">​</a></h3><p>Settle Aid considers the interests of "Flying Grannies", who are potentially impacted by our application. It prioritizes their interests in terms of safety, cultural familiarity, and social well-being.</p><ol><li>Advising Users: If any conflicts of interest or conscientious objections arise in the development or operation of the app, it advises the user as soon as possible with options to be excluded from the application. This transparency allows users to make informed decisions about using the app.</li><li>Respecting Intellectual Property: Settle Aid respects the intellectual property of others, ensuring that it does not infringe on copyrights, patents, or trademarks when providing educational content and recommendations.</li><li>Protecting Confidentiality and Privacy: Settle Aid is committed to preserving the confidentiality and privacy of user information. It implements robust data protection measures to safeguard user data and ensure that it is used only for the intended purposes, thereby respecting the privacy of others.</li></ol><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-enhancement-of-quality-of-life">The Enhancement of Quality of life<a href="#the-enhancement-of-quality-of-life" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Enhancement of Quality of life" title="Direct link to The Enhancement of Quality of life">​</a></h3><p>Settle Aid strives its best to have significant positive impact on our society and way of life, and minimize the consequent adverse effects. </p><ol><li>Health and Safety: The app prioritizes the health and safety of its users, "Flying Grannies." It does not engage in any practices that compromise their safety or well-being. Additionally, the app's navigation assistance includes safety considerations, such as suggesting safe routes and ensuring that users can efficiently carry out daily essential activities while minimizing potential safety risks.</li><li>Understanding Perceptions: Settle Aid acknowledges the importance of understanding and giving due regard to the perceptions of those affected by its services. It considers the cultural perceptions and preferences of "Flying Grannies" when offering recommendations and tips, ensuring that their cultural backgrounds are respected and valued.</li><li>Increasing Personal Satisfaction and Control: The app aims to increase the feelings of personal satisfaction, competence, and control of "Flying Grannies." By providing educational content, challenges and achievements for cultural integration, it empowers users to navigate Melbourne city with confidence, fostering a sense of personal satisfaction and control over their experiences.</li></ol><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="honesty">Honesty<a href="#honesty" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Honesty" title="Direct link to Honesty">​</a></h3><p>Settle Aid is designed to provide honest and accurate information to its users, including cultural tips and navigation support.</p><ol><li>Not Misleading Users: Settle Aid does not knowingly mislead its users about the suitability of its services. It provides accurate information about the purpose and functionality of the app, setting realistic expectations.</li><li>Qualifying Professional Opinions: Settle Aid qualifies professional opinions, especially in cases where recommendations are based on limited knowledge or experience. It does so by providing clear explanations of information to help users make informed decisions.</li><li>Cultural Integrity: Settle Aid does not attempt to enhance its reputation at the expense of another person's reputation. It promotes cultural diversity and inclusivity without diminishing or disparaging any particular culture or group.</li></ol><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="competence">Competence<a href="#competence" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Competence" title="Direct link to Competence">​</a></h3><p>Settle Aid complies with the most current industrial standards and legislation, respects user interests and utilize full expertise of colleagues in complementary areas.</p><ol><li>Not Misrepresenting Skills or Knowledge: Settle Aid does not misrepresent its skills or knowledge. It offers services within its scope and expertise, such as cultural tips, navigation assistance, and community recommendations, without making false claims about its capabilities.</li><li>Awareness of Standards and Legislation: Settle Aid is aware of relevant standards and legislation, particularly those related to data privacy, security, and cultural sensitivity. It acts in accordance with these standards and legal requirements to protect user interests.</li></ol><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="continuing-professional-development">Continuing Professional development<a href="#continuing-professional-development" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Continuing Professional development" title="Direct link to Continuing Professional development">​</a></h3><p>As the product evolves, Settle Aid should incorporate ongoing learning and improvements based on user feedback and emerging ethical considerations.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="professionalism">Professionalism<a href="#professionalism" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Professionalism" title="Direct link to Professionalism">​</a></h3><p>Settle Aid promotes professionalism by providing tools and resources that help "Flying Grannies" integrate into Australian society, demonstrating respect for cultural norms and ethical behavior.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>products</category>
            <category>ethics</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Future Sponsors]]></title>
            <link>https://topmello.github.io/blog/sponsors</link>
            <guid>https://topmello.github.io/blog/sponsors</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[- Melbourne City Council: Settle Aid is an easy mobile application for middle age users to spare time and motivate them to go out and visit landmarks, restaurants and shops. This promotes cultural diversity and social integration, enhancing the city's reputation as a welcoming and inclusive destination. Ultimately, it potentially boosts the local economy by exposing a new customer group.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul><li>Melbourne City Council: Settle Aid is an easy mobile application for middle age users to spare time and motivate them to go out and visit landmarks, restaurants and shops. This promotes cultural diversity and social integration, enhancing the city's reputation as a welcoming and inclusive destination. Ultimately, it potentially boosts the local economy by exposing a new customer group.</li><li>Uber: Trip attractions can be far apart and require a ride. Uber can potentially incorporate Settle Aid for people to share rides and further enhance cultural bridging if they go to the attraction together.</li><li>Trip Advisor: Trip Advisor is a website that emphasizes on traveller’s experience and satisfaction. With Settle Aid, trip advisor can target more audience groups and broaden customer market and potentially differentiate their product in this new group.</li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>products</category>
            <category>sponsors</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Mello Team]]></title>
            <link>https://topmello.github.io/blog/team</link>
            <guid>https://topmello.github.io/blog/team</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[| Name            | Details                                                                                                                  |]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<table><thead><tr><th>Name</th><th>Details</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Can Wang (Cam)</td><td><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/camwang/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Profile Link</a></td></tr><tr><td>Gordon Leung</td><td><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gordon-leung-65b28a112/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Profile Link</a></td></tr><tr><td>Jiashi Chen (Tony)</td><td><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tonychen0721/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Profile Link</a></td></tr><tr><td>Jincheng Song (Jasper)</td><td><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jasper-song-719727252/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Profile Link</a></td></tr><tr><td>Jirathip Kunkanjanathorn (Guy)</td><td><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jirathip-kunkanjanathorn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Profile Link</a></td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>products</category>
            <category>team</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
            <link>https://topmello.github.io/blog/welcome</link>
            <guid>https://topmello.github.io/blog/welcome</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Settle-Aid]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="settle-aid">Settle-Aid<a href="#settle-aid" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Settle-Aid" title="Direct link to Settle-Aid">​</a></h2><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="problem-statement">Problem Statement<a href="#problem-statement" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Problem Statement" title="Direct link to Problem Statement">​</a></h2><p>“Flying Grannies” in Australia are subjected to social isolation due to difficulty adapting to new surroundings. They make temporary visits to Melbourne for the purpose of looking after their grandchildren. With 30% of Australia's population originating from overseas, a minimum of 4,500 grandparents are undertaking regular brief trips to aid their families. These grandparents face challenges adapting to new environments due to language barrier and cultural shock, resulting in a tendency to remain at home. Frequently, they experience loneliness and are socially isolated, especially when their grandchildren are in school or during the early stages of their stay in Australia.</p><p>The impact of social isolation is detrimental to the well-being of grandparents, causing stress among family members and diminishing the multicultural fabric of Australian society. Given Melbourne's being a metropolitan city of diverse cultures with a significant number of grandparents, there is a dire need to facilitate connections between “Flying Grannies” and the broader community. </p><p>How might we mitigate the social isolation experienced by "Flying Grannies" in Melbourne and assist them in adapting to their new surroundings?</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="persona">Persona<a href="#persona" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Persona" title="Direct link to Persona">​</a></h2><table><thead><tr><th>Attribute</th><th>Details</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Name</td><td>Dalin Yu</td></tr><tr><td>Major Responsibility</td><td>Grandpa</td></tr><tr><td>Demographics</td><td>62 years old, Married with children and grandchildren, Non-proficient in English, Recently moved from China to Australia</td></tr><tr><td>Motivations</td><td>"Dalin wants to provide dedicated care for his grandson, ensuring his son able to work with peace of mind."</td></tr><tr><td>Motivations</td><td>He would embark on monthly travels with his friends if he feels less overwhelmed.</td></tr><tr><td>Pain point 1</td><td>Dalin is not familiar with any local activities and finds it difficult to navigate around the Melbourne city.</td></tr><tr><td>Pain point 2</td><td>Social isolation due to language hurdles and the challenges of adapting to a new local culture</td></tr></tbody></table><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="target-audience">Target Audience<a href="#target-audience" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Target Audience" title="Direct link to Target Audience">​</a></h2><p>Grandparents aged between 50 and 65 who make temporary visits to Melbourne for childcare purposes. This demographic demonstrates a higher proficiency in using smartphones compared to individuals aged 65 and above. They also show higher tendency to travel and adapt to different culture.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>products</category>
            <category>hello</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>